卸了輪子 拿了錢就走 別捅婁子
這次再把輪子搞壞 我一定要你們好看
快 動手
去那邊 夥計
都沒吃飯嗎
把收音機關掉
Turn down the fucking radio.
你想把警察引來還是想怎樣
看來這次能賺不少錢 夥計們
快點 快點 快點
見鬼
Fuck.
嘿 別把螺帽丟了 兄弟
快點 都放車上去
行了 動作輕點
得走了 夥計們
動作快 動作快
好了 好了 快好了
夥計們
Ah, Guys.
這些螺帽全是鍍鉻的 都被你們磨壞了
Those are chrome plated mugs. You can not strip them.
看看這傢伙
Look at this guy.
鍍層都被你們刮花了
The plating's flaked out.
是嗎？
Yeah?
這車是租來的 沒人會花錢開一輛...
You know, this is on lease. No one is gonna pay you like...
找死 繼續幹活兒
該死
Shit.
夥計們 夥計們
Guys, guys.
夥計們 說真的 你們會後悔的
Guys, seriously you don't wanna do this.
擺平他
Take him out.
不 別朝車開槍
No, not The car..
往死裏打
Kick that fool.
混蛋
Motherfuck..
該死
Shit.
見鬼
Fuck.
所有人都睡了 伯特
Everyone is asleep, Burt.
或者在夢遊 就像冰川融化 色情小說作家 有毒的水源 變種人
Sleepwalking between the ice caps, pornographers poisoned water, mutants...
其實他們都有聯繫
It's all connected.
嘿 克萊德 都已經2029年了
Hey, Clyde. It's 2029.
為什麼我們還要提起變種人
Why are we still talking about mutants?
是我 我在車上
Hey It's Me. I'm in the car.
對 旅途很愉快
Yes, it was a good trip.
幹完就走人
Tilt it up and down the fence.
美利堅 美利堅 美利堅
U.S.A! U.S.A! U.S.A! U.S.A! U.S.A! U.S.A!
金剛狼
Wolverine.
我知道是你
I knew it was you.
- 見鬼  - 請別走
- Oh, fuck.  - Please!
我有事相求
I am in trouble!
你是唯一能幫我們的人
You're the only one that could help!
我需要像你這樣的英雄
有多遠給我滾多遠
Get the fuck away from me!
你到底經歷了什麼？
為什麼要躲起來
求你了
Please!
羅根
Logan!
那人是誰
Who is that?
不知道哪兒來的瘋女人 不必擔心
I do not know, some crazy lady. Don't worry.
真是百聞不如一見 金剛狼
As I live and breath, The Wolverine.
可惜他成了癮君子
And he is a junkie now.
你又是誰
Who the fuck are you?
你車門上怎麼有彈孔啊
You know, you got some buck shot on your door.
我聽說你在鳳凰城
I heard you was in Phoenix.
可昨晚我德州的朋友打來電話
But then last night some friends of mine at Texas HP called.
說在54號公路旁的水塘裏發現3具墨西哥人的屍體
Told me they found 3 dead cholos in the pool out on 54.
很平常 對吧
Not unusual, I know.
不過有具少只手 還有具少只腿
Except one was missing a hand another one a leg.
這讓他們覺得
So they was thinking...
可能是脫逃的老虎 或者《猛鬼街》裏的佛瑞迪干的
It was either an escaped tiger or Freddy Kruger.
可是他們不可能會開車啊
But neither one of them can drive...
一個是電影虛構的 另一個已經滅絕了
One being fictional and the other one extinct.
而且他們找到的車輪防滑釘是克萊斯勒上的
And since the wheel lugs they found belong to a 24 Chrysler...
剛好
Well...
你開的就是克萊斯勒
This is a 24 Chrysler.
她找到你了嗎
She found you yet?
加芙列拉
Gabriella?
聽著
See...
我要找的不是你 狼叔
I'm not looking for you, Wolvie.
確切的說我要找的人恰巧在找你
Well, not really, I'm looking for someone who's looking for you.
她趁我不注意時帶走了我的一樣東西
She took me something of mine when I wasn't looking.
一樣我要擔責任的東西
Something for which I am responsible.
一個墨西哥女人
A Mexican lady
她正在找你
Has its eyes on you now.
沒想起什麼嗎
Doesn't ring any bells?
我不認識什麼加芙列拉 所以趕緊給我滾
I don't know any Gabriella. So get the fuck out of my car.
知道嗎
You know?
我知道你把誰藏了起來 朋友
I know what you hiding amigo.
你把老光頭藏在了墨西哥邊境
The old cue ball south of the border
你想怎麼樣
What do you want?
我只想你合作
A little cooperation.
差點忘了 你是我的偶像
I'm a fan, by the way.
阿爾卡利 基因改造研究所
安全部主任 唐納德·皮爾斯
該死 該死
Fuck! Fuck!
不 愛斯佩蘭薩先生 不
No, Miss Morales. No.
是說好六月 可我現在就需要那艘船
I know I said June, but I need the boat now,
為什麼這樣就得漲價
Why would that mean the price go up.
聽著
Listen...
我知道你想要7萬
I know you wanted 7...
好吧 如果我能一次性給你4萬5現金呢
Ok. What if I can put together $45,000 cash right now?
喂 喂
Hello? Hello?
見鬼
Shit.
你即將離開美國境內
嘿 山姆
Hey, Sam.
早上好
Good Morning.
他今天情況不太好
He's having a bad day.
哪天情況好過了
They're all bad days.
六個小時前他就該服藥了
He needed these six hours ago.
你知道這些根本不夠
This is not enough, you know.
一星期都撐不過
Won't see us through the week
我會想辦法的
I'm working on it.
輪到你了
Your turn.
我都折騰了一晚上了
I had a rough night.
好吧 你可以的
Well. Poor you.
還有件事 他昨晚和我說他在和某個人神交
In other news, he told me last night he was communicating with someone.
沒人和他神交
He's not talking to anybody.
話別說那麼絕對
Don't be so sure.
他還交代了很多細節
He has got all these details.
我還以為那個蓄水箱能把他隔絕起來
I thought that tank was supposed to act as a barrier.
- 可他發作起來根本不管用  - 求你消停會兒
- It has gotten cracks in it.  - Please stop.
左邊下面
Bottom left.
你沒在聽我說話
You're not listening.
他又開始不停地問問題了 問為什麼我們會在這兒
He's been asking questions again. That why we're here.
我覺得他還想鑽進我的意識裏
I think he's trying to read my mind.
所以我們才要給他餵藥
That's what these are for.
朋友們 我有個好消息要告訴你們
Friends, I have good news for you today!
你們做什麼並不重要
It's not about what you do.
做什麼也不重要 你們只是無法按照
It's not about your deed. You gotta give up to God.
上帝的旨意而活 沒關係 我們並非完人
He knows what you can't. It's Okay, we are imperfect.
請讓一下 先生
Make way, sir.
我說了讓開
I said make way!
來自塔可鍾快餐店的新墨西哥雞肉卷
The new "quesalupa" from Taco Bell!
加一份雞肉 加一份牛排
Get it with chicken, get it with steak
還有包裹著濃郁芝士在火上慢烤的餅皮
Get it with the cheescake right in the sell.
新一季的明星產品
It's the next big thing.
還不快來搶
Call now, while supplies last!
你是誰
Who are you?
你知道我是誰
You know who I am.
你是那個總讓我睡覺的傢伙
You're the man who puts me to sleep.
我們都需要睡會兒
We both can use some sleep.
不 拿開 快拿開
No go! No Go!
你想對我做什麼
What are you doing to me?
查爾斯
Charles.
別這樣
Come on.
我待在這兒多久了
How long have I been here?
這是什麼
What are these?
你知道這是什麼
You remember what they are.
打針可以緩解痙攣 按時吃藥就不會發作了
Shocks and all the seizures. The pills keep those from happening.
不如你吹口僊氣 願上帝保佑吧
How 'bout you blow on them to make you safe.
去你的 羅根
Fuck off, Logan.
所以你想起來我是誰了
So, you remember who I am now.
我一直都知道你是誰
I always know who you are.
只是有的時候沒認出來而已
But sometimes I don't recognize you.
快吃藥吧
Take the pills.
你把我一個人丟給那個有白化病的傢伙
You leave me alone with that fucking albino.
他根本不聽我說話
He doesn't listen to me.
我一看就知道他們是新的物種
I know a damn speciation when I see one.
什麼
What?
新的物種 新的變種人 很年輕
Speciation, a new mutant, a young one.
- 有勢力想要屠殺他們  - 勢力
- There are forces trying to kill them. - Forces?
他們需要幫助
They want help.
勢力 勢力
Forces, forces.
可惜你已經退出歷史舞台了
Too bad you are not in that business anymore.
他們需要的不是我 而是你
They don't want me, they want you.
好吧 他們還真是愚不可及
Oh yeah... That's how fucking stupid they are.
他們在自由女神像那兒等著你
They're waiting for you at the Statue Of Liberty.
自由女神像早就沒了 查爾斯 都已經多少年了
Statue of Liberty was a long time ago, Charles. A long time.
早就沒有新的變種人了 明白嗎
There are no new mutants. You understand?
已經有25年沒有新的變種人出生了
There hasn't been a new one born in 25 years. Not anywhere.
你總是以為
We always thought...
我們是上帝計劃的一部分
We were part of God's plan.
或許吧
Maybe...
又或者我們是上帝犯下的錯誤
May be we were God's mistake.
你太讓我失望了
What a disappointment you are.
當年我找到你的時候
When I found you...
你還只是個做困獸之鬥的拳手
You were persuing your career as a cage fighter.
這對於殺手來說已經是個不錯的歸宿了
A life of an assassin
靠嗑藥為生
hooked on barbiturates.
當時的你就是個野獸
You were an animal.
是我們接納了你
But we took you in.
給了你一個溫馨的家
I gave you a family.
可現在都沒了
They are gone now.
羅根
Logan.
Logan...
你到底做了什麼
What did you do?
回答我 為什麼我們會在這兒
Answer me! Why are we here?
這不是我該過的生活
No one should live like this.
在這破水箱裏被藥物麻痹
Drugged in a fucking tank!
- 這是為了你好  - 不 不對 這不是為了我好
- It's for your own good.  - No no, it's not!
你只是在等我死
You're waiting for me to die.
我不想吵架
I don't want to fight...
但有些事情總得商量著解決
but there's things we need to discuss.
什麼事
What things?
好吧 你別嫌我嘮叨
Well, would it be considered nagging?
我之前就已經和你說過了
If I was to repeat my previous observation
這些劑量太少了 沒法抑制他的痙攣
that the dose is too low to suppress the seizures
那傢伙就給我這些
It's what the guy gave me.
我沒什麼資格討價還價
I was not in a position to make demands.
今早我差點就死在這兒了
I almost dying this morning.
- 每次他一發作  - 連一分鐘都沒到
- That seizure...  - It was barely a minute.
感覺根本不止一分鐘 我都無法呼吸了
It felt a lot longer than a minute. I could not breathe.
你受到的影響比我小
You are less affected.
你知道該增加劑量了
You know he needs a higher dose.
我還知道你藏了不少錢
And I know you got more money squirreled away.
那些錢是用來帶我們離開這裏的
Money to get us out of here.
不 不是我們 是你和他
No, not us. You and him.
你想買一艘「逐日號」遊艇
You're saving to buy a sun seeker.
「日」字是關鍵
Sun is the key word.
我不覺得自己能像不死殭屍那樣一輩子躲在船艙裏
I hardly see myself cowering below deck like Nosferatu
不是嗎
Do you?
在那兒疊著你的短褲 給他做葡萄乾布丁
Folding your underpants, And making him spotted dick
在你口袋裏找到的
Found this in your pocket.
艾德曼合金
Adamantium.
如果你想讓自己的腦袋開花
If you're planning to blow your brains out...
請到了公海再動手吧
Could you wait till we're out on the high seas?
- 我剛把地板拖乾淨  - 別和我說這些廢話
- I just mopped these floors.  - I don't need this shit.
一年前 你找我來幫忙
A year ago, you asked me to help you.
我發誓我盡力了
God knows I've tried.
可如果你不肯對我說出實情的話
But I can't help you, Logan, not really...
我想我沒法幫到你
if you are not gonna talk to me.
你晚上總是不睡覺 我能聽見
I hear you at night. You are not sleeping
你不想和我談談嗎
You don't wanna talk about that.
還有你喝酒的事
Or the booze you're drinking.
還有手指間被你擦掉的膿水
Or the pus you are wiping away from your knuckles.
或者我洗衣服時看到的血跡
Or the blood I wash in your clothes
又或者你胸口上的新傷口
Or the fresh wounds in your chest.
那些沒有癒合的傷口
The ones that aren't healing.
以及我很肯定
And I'm pretty sure..
你已經看不清瓶子上的標籤了
You don't want to talk about the fact that you can't read the label on that bottle.
上面寫的是布洛芬
It says ibuprofen.
那是我最喜歡的馬克杯
That was my favorite mug
不用你多管閒事
Stay out of my shit.
我知道你出問題了 羅根
Something is happening to you, Logan.
在你的體內 你病了 我聞得出來
On the inside you're sick. I can smell it.
這是我最嗨的一晚
Best night ever!
我愛你 我也愛你
I love you. I love you.
你太可愛了
You are such a doll.
兩名乘客 自由汽車旅館
羅根先生
Mr. Logan.
天啊
Jesus.
求你了 我們需要搭車
Please. We need a ride.
我沒空 叫出租車吧
I am not available. Call a cab.
- 我叫加芙列拉·洛佩茲  - 我不想知道 女士
- My name is Gabriella Lopez.  - I don't wanna know your name lady.
有人在追殺我們
There are men after us.
我們必須離開這兒
We need to get out of here.
往北走 去加拿大
Go north, cross to Canada.
這活兒誰都能幹
Anyone can do that job.
我可以給你5萬美元
I'll give you $ 50,000.
你是怎麼找到我的 你帶給我的麻煩已經夠多的了
How did you find me huh? You are fucking up my life lady.
追你們的那幫人現在盯上我了
The people after you, they are on my ass now.
你被人認出來了
Sightings were posted.
- 勞拉 到裏面去  - 被誰認出來了
- Lauda, go inside.  - What sightings?
有人說看到一個長得很像金剛狼的人 在厄爾巴索當司機
People said someone look like the wolverine was seen at Paso driving.
還說他看上去老了
said he looked old.
嘿
Hey!
我警告過你別再玩那個球了
I told you to stop it with that ball.
- 你這個臭丫頭  - 不 求你了
- Bad girl.  - No, no, no please!
- 我警告過你 臭丫頭  - 不 求你了
- I told you, bad girl!  - No Please.
- 你可得賠錢給我  - 求你了 別說了
- gonna have to pay for that.  - Stop Please.
見鬼
Shit!
他們得賠償我的損失
They gonna have to pay for damages.
她身上有錢
And she has cash.
我看到的
I've seen it.
帶著你的肥臀滾回你的辦公室
You get your fat ass back in your office.
她會賠你錢的
She will get your money.
別讓她打給任何人了 求你了
Don't let her call anyone. Please.
他們會找到我們的 然後殺了我們
They'll find us, they'll kill us.
我是名護士
I'm a nurse.
曾經是 在墨西哥城
Was, In Mexico City.
什麼時候受傷的
When did that happen?
今天早上 在邊界處
This morning. Near the border.
我逃了出來 不過
I got away from them, but...
由於缺少新生變種人 研究人員備受困擾
水中是否被添加了某種物質
基因改造
兒科癌癥研究
現在他們認得我的車了
Now they know my car.
聽著 我得走了
Look, I gotta go.
不 等等 求你了
No wait, wait. Please. Here.
等等 快看
Please wait! Look. Look,
給你 你拿著 這裏是2萬美元
Look. Here, Take this. It's $ 20,000.
拿著 帶我們去上面的地址
Here. Take us to this address.
等你到了那兒我再給你3萬
You are gonna have $ 30,000 more when we get there.
我朋友到時候會給你
My friends, he will give it to you.
他們在等我們
They will be waiting.
你要什麼他們都會給你的
They will give you anything.
這些錢哪兒來的
Where did you get this?
我男朋友的
My boyfriend.
他想要殺了我 然後帶走她
He wants to kill me and take her.
那是你女兒
That's your daughter?
是的
Yes.
我知道你是個好人
I know you're still good inside.
我知道你會幫我們的
I know you want to help us.
- 你根本不瞭解我  - 求你了
- You don't know anything about me.  - Please!
我保證 如果現在就走的話 不會有事的
I promise, there will be no problems if we leave now.
我不能就這麼離開去北達科他州
I can't just leave to North Dakota!
- 我們必須週五前趕到那兒  - 否則怎樣
- We have to be there Friday.  - For what?
否則我們就沒法過境
Or we miss our chance to cross.
求你了
Please.
幫幫我們 求你了
You have to. Please.
求你了
Please.
我喜歡你的老花鏡
I like those.
這樣看上去年輕點
They make you look younger.
- 請快點  - 在路上了
查爾斯 聽著 我得走了
Charles, listen. I gotta go uh,
我可能要離開幾天 好嗎
I gotta go away for a few days. Okay?
我得跑趟長途掙筆大錢
I got a long ride, get some good money
回來後我們就離開這裏
When I get back, we gonna get out of here.
我們開車去葉萊巴 然後再買艘船
We're gonna drive down to Yelapa. We're gonna get ourselves a boat.
從此就住在海上
And we gonna go live on the ocean.
到那兒就會安全了
Will you be safe there?
是的 當然 我們會安全的
Yeah, yeah, we'll be safe.
看羅根給我們帶了什麼 查爾斯
Know what Logan got us Charles?
過幾天就回來
I will be back in a few days.
見鬼
Shit.
他們來了 請你...
- 羅根  - 什麼？
- Logan. - Yeah?
發生什麼事了
What happened?
出什麼事了嗎
Did something go wrong?
這活兒一開始就是個錯誤
Job was wrong when I get there.
羅根
Logan!
幹嘛
What?
這些東西是誰的
Who does this belong to?
那是誰
Who is that?
你為什麼沒能預見這破事
Weren't you supposed to see shit coming.
我可以追蹤變種人
I can track mutants.
我能嗅出很多東西 可我不是千里眼
I'm a glorified truffle pig not a clairvoyant.
到裏面去 別讓查爾斯出聲 到裏面去 快
Go inside, Keep Charles quiet. Go inside Now!
調頭出去 混蛋 這是私人領地
You need to turn around, assholes. This is private property.
是的 沒錯
Yes it is.
事實上我記得這裏應該屬於一家總部在上海的
In fact, I believe it belongs to a Multinational Smelting company...
跨國冶煉公司
based in Shanghai.
你把老傢伙藏哪兒了
Where are you keeping the old man?
他在裏面嗎
Is it over there?
還是在這裏
Or is he there?
點子不錯
That would be smart.
我想見見他
I would like to meet him.
我聽說國土安全局已經把他的大腦列為大規模殺傷性武器了
I'm told HS classifies his brain as a weapon of mass destruction now.
在東部發生的事真是可惜了
Damn shame what happened back in east.
他已經死了一年了
He's been dead for a year.
我需要那女孩兒
I need the girl.
什麼女孩兒
What girl?
你手裏那只球的主人
One that goes along with that ball you're holding.
這裏沒有女孩兒
There is no girl here.
我知道你去過那家汽車旅館
I know you went to the motel.
是的 有人訂了車
Yeah, I was called there.
沒有女孩兒 只有一個女人
There was no girl. there was Just a woman.
只有一個女人 說得沒錯
Just a woman. Such as she was.
那麼 你見過加芙列拉了
So you saw Gabriela.
可你沒有打給我 真是傷心
But you did not call me. That hurts.
該不會是你朝她開的槍吧
You didn't shoot the both of them, did you?
- 不 你呢  - 是我先問你的
- No, did you?  - I asked you first.
- 我不喜歡用槍  - 當然了
- I don't like guns.  - Of course.
真希望你有打給我 羅根
I wish you would call me Logan.
按照我說的那樣
Like I asked.
看見沒
See?
不是只有你一個人被改造過
You are not the only one who's been enhanced.
羅根 羅根
Logan. Logan!
這位是勞拉
This is Laura.
卡利班 快來
Caliban, come!
這位就是我一直和你提起的
This the who I've been telling you about.
這位是勞拉
This is Laura.
我們一直都在等你
We've been waiting for you.
我們一直都在等你（西班牙語）
過來 快過來
Come, come here.
沒事了
It's okay.
過來
Come.
勞拉
Laura.
沒事了 沒事了
It's ok, it's okay.
過來
Come
Come.
來吧 沒事的 你可以留在這兒 勞拉
Come. It's okay. You can stay here, Laura.
這兒很安全
It's safe.
在這兒我們可以照顧你 來吧
We can look after for you, come on.
看著像退役軍人 也可能是個賞金獵人
Looks like ex military. Bounty hunter maybe?
更糟
Worse.
就他一個人？
Is he by himself?
對 但只是暫時的
Yeah, not for long.
把他搬上車 扔到干河床那兒去
Get him back in his ride take him out to the wash and dump him.
如果他半路醒了怎麼辦
And what he wakes up before I get there.
發消息告訴我你在哪兒 我們去接你
Text me where you are. We will pick you up.
對 沒錯
Si, si
羅根
Logan.
- 羅根  - 嘿 嘿
- Logan.  - Hey. Hey!
等我搞明白你和你媽媽的來龍去脈 我會還給你的
You will get it back after I figure out what you and your mother have got us into.
- 不 羅根  - 幹嘛
- No, Logan.  - What?
我覺得 你可能
I don't, I think...
羅根 你遇到的那個女人並不是她的媽媽
Logan, the woman that you met It's not her mother.
- 所以她會說話  - 我們一直都有交流
- So she talks?  - We are communicating.
交流 好吧
Communicating.
快把這些藥吃了
Take these now.
我們得馬上離開 這裏已經不安全了
We have to get out of here. It's not safe here anymore.
你不能在外面發作 明白嗎
And you can't have an attack out there you understand?
好的 可她就是我告訴你的那個新變種人
Yes, but this is the mutant that I told you about.
- 她需要幫助  - 她不是變種人
- She needs our help.  - She's not a mutant.
- 不 她是變種人  - 那她的天賦是什麼 查爾斯
- Yes she is!   - What's her gift, Charles?
- 吃東西 還是扔鋼管  - 羅根
- Eating? pipe Throwing?  - Logan.
沒事的
It's okay.
沒事的 只是火車經過
小火車 只是火車經過而已
別擔心 火車而已
好了
Oh yeah.
拿著槍 把屍體扔了
"Take the gun. Dump the body".
回來的時候發消息給我
"Text me when you're on the way back"
還有什麼需要的嗎 孩子吃的食物
Is there anything else you need. Anything for the kid?
這下你完蛋了 變種人
You're fucked now, muty.
別擔心
It's ok.
只是另一輛火車經過而已
這次不是火車了
沒事的 坐下吧
It's ok. Sit down.
- 我們得走了  - 什麼
- We gotta go.  - What?
- 出什麼事了  - 待在這兒 去哪兒
- What's going on?  - Stay here. Where?
- 別亂動  - 我們要去哪兒
- Don't move.  - Where are we going?
別擔心 他會回來找你的
Don't worry. He'll be back for you.
羅根 那女孩兒 你得回去接那女孩兒
Logan, the girl. Don't go. We gotta go back for the girl.
羅根 那女孩兒怎麼辦
Logan, what about the girl?
羅根
Logan.
羅根 我們不能丟下勞拉
Logan, we mustn't forget about Laura.
她不歸我們管
She's not our problem.
見鬼
Shit!
（西班牙語）
羅根
Logan.
嗯 我在想辦法
Yeah, I'm thinking.
那個孩子
The child.
羅根 我們不能丟下勞拉
Logan, we mustn't forget Laura.
- 求你別說了  - 羅根
- Please be quite.  - Logan.
- 查爾斯·澤維爾  - 卡利班在哪兒
- Charles Xavier.  - Where's Caliban?
美國頭號八旬通緝犯
America's most wanted Octogenarian.
準確說我已經九十多歲了
I'm an Nonagenarian, actually.
卡利班在哪兒
Where is Caliban?
不如你先告訴我那女孩兒在哪兒
Why don't you tell me where the girl is first.
或者我可以問老光頭 他看起來比較友善
Or I can ask cue ball. He seems quite friendly.
我說了 她不在我這裏
I told you she's not here.
卡利班在哪兒 你這個混蛋
Where is Caliban, motherfucker?
我把他扔到了原本你為我預留的溝裏
I left him in the same ditch he was gonna leave me.
天啊 金剛狼 看到你這副樣子我真是太心碎了
Jesus, Wolverine, seeing you like this just breaks my damn heart.
真不想親手把你的心挖出來碾碎
As soon as I rip it out of your chest, fuck.
把她帶來
Go get her.
勞拉
Laura!
就是她
Atta girl!
嘿 寶貝
Hey baby.
勞拉
Laura...
Laura!
寶貝 待在原地別動
Honey, you wanna stay where you are.
你想見你的朋友是嗎
You want to see your friends, right?
打死那個變種人
指揮官 別這樣
Commander, just stop.
你不是說無論生死嗎
You said alive or dead.
勞拉
Laura!
Laura.
勞拉
不 不
No no.
動手 快
Move!... Go
開槍 快
Move! Now!
停止射擊
Stop shooting.
- 她能自愈 快追  - 好了 去追
- She heals! Move!  - All right move out.
我早就告訴你了 羅根 她和你一樣是變種人
As I told you Logan, She is a mutant like you.
坐穩了
Hold on!
和你非常像
Very much like you.
勞拉 你沒事吧
Laura, are you alright?
快追
Move!
坐穩了
Hold on.
該死 快啊
Fuck! Oh Come on!
快啊
Come on!
列陣 給我追
All in, let's go.
坐回去
Sit back.
把追蹤者帶來
Bring me the tracker.
你
You.
你到底是誰
Who the hell are you?
嘿 我在問你話呢 你是誰
Hey! I asked you a question. Who are you?
你知道他是誰 羅根
You know who she is, Logan.
不 我不知道
No, I don't
你不覺得她很像誰嗎
Does she remind you of anybody?
我小的時候讀到過你的故事
I read about you when I was a kid.
我想你認錯人了
I believe you're thinking of someone else,
如果我沒記錯 你曾經也為我們效過力吧
Now if I'm not mistaken, you used to work for my team.
你幫我們圍捕過那些變種人
You were helping round up all those old mutants.
現在怎麼變了
What changed?
你信教了？
You got religion?
我需要你幫我們這樣的好人再做一件事
I'm gonna need you to do one more thing for the good guys...
再幫我追蹤一個特別的變種人
and track one more special mutant for me.
我不會幫你的
I'm not helping you.
你知道你會這麼說
Of course you would say that.
不過我總覺得人的本質是不會變的
But I've got a theory that people don't really change.
小心光
Beware of the light.
卡利班 我猜小時候 你媽媽肯定每天都這麼和你說吧
Caliban, I bet that's what your mama told you everyday when you was a kid.
小心光
Beware of the light.
好了 別讓我們互相撕破臉皮
Let's not bring out the worst in it, shall we?
為了那女孩兒不值得
The girl is not worth it, trust me.
你們不一樣 她生下來不是變種人
She is not a natural fuck up like you.
他是公司犯下的錯誤 研發失誤
She's a business mistake, R&D going bad
就是個累贅
There's liability.
不能就這麼讓專利產品到處亂跑 傷害無辜不是嗎
They can't have things with patent running around hurting people, can they?
在她傷害別人之前 我們得把她帶回去
We need to get her off the board before she hurts anybody else.
或許下一個就是你在乎的人
Someone you care about.
好好聞一聞吧
So get to sniffing.
我叫做加芙列拉·洛佩茲
My name is Gabriella Lopez.
我是名護士
I'm a nurse.
過去十年我一直在為墨西哥城的基因改造研究所工作
And for 10 years I worked for Transigen research in Mexico City.
該研究所屬於一家美國公司
Transigen is owned by an American company.
接下來你們看到的 在美國和加拿大
What I'm about to show you is illegal...
都是非法的
in the US and Canada.
阿爾卡利實驗室 實驗備忘錄
桑德爾·萊斯博士 癌癥項目主管
他說我們是研究藥物的
They told us we were part of a pharmaceutical study.
當然 這都是騙人的
But Of course, that was a lie.
這些孩子都出生在研究所裏
These children were born in Transigen.
他們出生在這裏
They were born here...
然後就再也沒離開過
and have never left.
他們從來沒見過陽光和大海
They have never seen the sun or the ocean...
雨水或飄雪
rain or snow...
或者上帝的其他造物
or any of God's creatures.
他們沒有出生證明
They have no birth certificates...
沒有名字
No names...
除了我們給他們的代號
besides the ones we have given them.
他們都是在墨西哥女孩的肚子裏孕育出來的
They were raised in the bellies of Mexican Girls.
孩子出生後女孩兒就再也找不到了
Girls no one can't find anymore.
他們的父親都是些
Their fathers were...
基因種子
Special seeds in bottles.
有過生日嗎
Birthday?
瑪利亞 萬聖節別給孩子打扮
Maria, we do not dress them for Halloween
別叫他們寶貝 也別叫他們親親
We do not call them baby, or kiss..
別把他們看作孩子 當他們是產品
Don't think them as children. Think them as things...
有專利有版權的產品
with patents and copyrights.
- 明白嗎  - 明白
- Comprende?  - Si seneor.
他們以為我們又窮又傻根本不理解
They thought we were too poor and stupid to understand.
我們是很窮
We are poor, yes...
可我們並不傻
but we are not stupid.
運用你的能力
Use your powers.
這是樁生意
This is business.
他們在製造士兵
They are making soldiers.
殺人機器
Killers.
這些年幼的變種人
These are babies of mutantes...
北達科他州
North Dakota.
你拿了那女人的錢
You took that woman's money.
你答應會帶那孩子去那兒的
You said you would take the child there.
他是什麼人
What is she?
她是你女兒 羅根
She is your daughter, Logan.
阿爾卡利有你的遺傳密碼
Alkali has your genetic code.
不只是我的
Not just mine.
羅根
Logan...
我不想談這事兒 也不想聽你再說下去
I do not want to talk about I don't wanna hear about it anymore.
- 羅根  - 別再說了
- Logan...  - Just stop.
我想尿尿
I have to pee.
最後一次
Last ride.
不客氣
You're welcome.
住手 看在上帝的份上 我自己能行
Stop it for God's sake, I can do this myself.
對 可你並沒有成功 趕緊尿吧
yeah. But, you're not doing it, just get on with it.
你站在那我怎麼尿
Not with you standing there.
放心 我不會偷看的
Trust me, I'm not looking.
小姑娘
Hello!
你好
Hi there!
知道吃東西要給錢吧
You know you got to pay for that, right?
你爸爸媽媽在哪裏
Hey! Where's your Mommy and Daddy huh?
過來
Come on.
鬧夠了 這個給我
That's enough.. These too.
不能這樣
Not okay!
抱歉
I am sorry.
手機充電器有嗎
Cell phone chargers?
快走 到車上去
Come on. In the car.
隨著孩子慢慢長大
As the children became older...
勞拉 勞拉
Laura. Laura.
他們變得越來越難相處
They became more difficult.
我們控制不了他們
They were not to be controlled.
公司把他們變成了武器
The company made their bodies into weapons.
開始教他們如何殺人
They tried to teach them to kill.
可他們不想戰鬥
But they do not want to fight.
不想打仗的士兵對他們來說毫無意義
A soldier who'll not fight is useless.
在這棟大樓裏
Inside this building...
他們還在研究新的東西
They are working on something new.
一個比這些孩子更強的東西
Something they think is better than the children.
他們說那是個沒有靈魂的東西
Something They say is without a soul.
身份代碼：X-24
他們肯定已經成功了
They must have been successful.
大約一周以前 他們告訴我們要停止項目
About a week ago, they told us to shut our programme down.
他們開始對那些孩子實施安樂死
They start putting children to sleep.
我們要救出盡可能多的孩子
We want to save as many children as we can.
我知道一個地方 在北方
I read about a place up North.
一個屬於變種人的地方
A place for mutants.
他們稱之為伊甸園
They call it Eden.
如果你看到了這段視頻
If you're watching this...
那證明我已經死了
It means that I'm dead.
我不知道還有沒有其他倖存下來的孩子
I am not sure if any other children survived.
我們走散了
We were separated.
沒有另一筆錢
There is no more money.
是我騙了你
That was a lie.
她不是我的孩子
She's not my child
可我愛她
But I love her.
你可能不會像我一樣愛她
You may not love her.
可她是你的孩子
But she's your child.
求你了 我請求你
Please. I beg you...
把她送到安全的地方
take her to safety.
我們要躲在這裏嗎
So this is where we're hiding out?
我們不躲
Hiding out?
找個地方睡幾個小時
We'll get a couple of hours sleep...
清洗一下 找幾件新衣服 換倆新車離開這裏
Clean up, get some new clothes, get a new ride, get out of here.
嘿
Hey.
就停在門口 好嗎
Hey, leave it out front, all right?
快點 我們走
Come on let's go.
嘿 勞拉
Hey, Laura.
我們走
Let's go.
我們需要衣服
We need clothes.
電梯上行
Going up.
不 住手 這不是玩具
No, no, stop. These are not toy.
- 不 不 不 抱歉 有輪椅  - 好吧
- No, no, sorry. The chair.  - What? okay.
謝謝
Thank you.
過來 站好 站好了
Come here. Stay there. Stand there.
羅根 這個給你
Logan, it is yours.
什麼
What?
現在不用 等到了房間裏我再換
Nothing to worry now, just in the room, get changed in the room.
你這個卑鄙的美國佬
Your nothing but a low-down lyin' Yankee!
拿出證據
Prove it.
原野奇俠 Shane (1953)
這是一部很有名的電影 勞拉
This is a very famous picture, Laura.
都快有一百年了
It's almost a 100 years old.
我第一次看這部電影 是在我家鄉的埃索達電影院裏
I first saw this picture in the Essoldo cinema in my own town...
當時我和你差不多大
when I was your age.
願人都尊你的名為聖 願你的國降臨
You are in Heaven, hallowed be thy name.
願你的旨意行在地上
Thy Kingdom come, thy will be done...
基因改造
兒科癌癥研究
見鬼
Shit.
已植入艾德曼金屬
基因源：詹姆斯·豪利特
《非凡X戰警》
你平時就看這個？
Do you read this in your spare time?
看啊 查爾斯 X戰警有新粉絲了
Oh yeah, Charles, We have ourselves an X man fan.
你知道裏面都是瞎寫的吧
You do know they are all bullshit right?
可能其中四分之一確有其事 但也不是這樣
Maybe a quarter bit happens, and not like this.
在現實世界裏人會死
In the real world, people die.
也沒有穿著緊身衣 自命不凡的傻子來救他們
And no who self promoting asshole in a fucking leotard.
這就是用來安慰失敗者的冰激凌
This is ice cream for Bed wake.
羅根
Logan...
那女的一直都在給她灌輸美麗的童話
The nurse has been feeding her some great bullshit.
我覺得勞拉不需要別人提醒她生命無常
I don't think that Laura needs reminding of life's impermanence.
你不是說要找輛新車嗎
Didn't you say something about finding us a new ride?
一個小時後吃兩粒
Two more pills in one hour.
記得給他
Give them to him.
為什麼 謝恩
Why, Shane?
人必須忠於自己 喬伊
A man has to be what he is, Joey.
不能違背自己的本性
Can't break the moulds.
我試過了 可最終還是不行
I tried, that didn't work for me.
喬伊 帶著殺戮活下去很艱難
Joey, there is no living with killing...
這條路沒有退路
There is no going back.
是對是錯 你都得背負
Right or wrong it is a brand.
直至一生
A brand sticks.
現在快回去找你媽媽 告訴她一切都好
Now you run on home to your mother and tell her everything is all right.
山谷裏再不會有槍聲了
There are no more guns in the valley.
你們是誰
Who are you guys?
又是警察？ 可我已經把我知道的都告訴了
More cops? cause I told the other guys...
暫停營業
起來 到籠子裏去 追蹤者
Get up! In your cage, tracker.
已經沒你的事了
You did your job.
夥計們
Fellas.
見鬼
Shit.
送你們了
Knock yourself out.
最低8000
Tell you what. Eight grand...
我可以幫你噴新漆 換一下輪胎 安裝調試好
I'll have it freshly painted for you, new tires, mounted, balanced
再幫你把手續辦了
and complete paperwork.
我給你10000 手續的事就跳過吧
I'll give you ten as it is if you can forget the paperwork.
你還是需要換輪胎 不換不行
Well, you still need new tires. Man, they're bald.
多久能辦好
How long will that take?
一個小時
An hour.
伊甸園 還是終結？
搞什麼鬼
Jesus.
北達科他州
這是在逗我嗎
You gotta be fuckin' kidding me
先生 你的鑰匙
Sir, your keys in it...?
你的鑰匙在車裏嗎 先生
You have the keys in it? Sir!
該死
Shit!
查爾斯 查爾斯
Charles. Charles!
見鬼
Shit!
你沒事吧
You all right?
我們得趕緊離開
We gotta get out of here.
我很抱歉
I am so sorry.
真的很抱歉
緊急救護人員仍在
Emergency personnel is still on scene
俄克拉荷馬市的哈利士賭場旅館
At Harrah's Casino and Hotel in Oklahoma City
昨日至少400人出現暫時性麻痹癥狀
where at least 400 guest was striken with temporary paralysis yesterday.
受傷情況大都和一年前的韋斯切斯特事故十分相似
many are showing a similarity to the Westchester incident over a year ago...
當時有超過600人受傷
that left over 600 injured...
7名變種人身亡 其中包括幾名X戰警
And took the lives of seven mutants including sevaral of the X men.
別玩了
Knock it off.
讓你別玩了
I said knock it off!
她只是個孩子 羅根
She's a child, Logan.
事實上 她是你的
And point of fact, She is your...
上次吃藥是什麼時候
How long has it been since you took your meds?
- 告訴我 隔了多久  - 我不知道
- Tell me, how long has it been?  - You know!
兩天吧
Two days.
昨天發生的事你也看到了
You saw what happened yesterday.
要不是我及時趕到
If that shit had gone on any longer...
我只是盡我所能保護勞拉
I did what I had to do to save Laura
你什麼都做不了
You didn't do anything.
你只是受了驚嚇發病了而已
You just freaked out and had a fucking siezure.
我想你更喜歡我吃了藥像瘋子一樣 語無倫次的模樣吧
I guess you prefer me pharmaceutically castrated rambling on like a lunatic
這樣你就能輕鬆些
So much easier for you.
輕鬆個屁
Easier? Jesus.
和你在一起就不會輕鬆 從來不會
There is nothing easy back here. Charles, Nothing!
就像這世上其他人一樣
Please be like the rest of the world.
把自己的過錯都怪罪到別人頭上
Blaming someone else for your boring shit.
我懂 老爹 你對我太失望了
I know. I'm such a giant disappointed.
你真的打心底不明白
You honestly derived no sense of purpose.
我們為什麼要這麼做嗎
from what we are doing?
好吧 那我們到底在做什麼
Okay, what are we doing?
有一個新生的變種人坐在我們的車上
There is a young mutant sitting in our car.
對 沒錯
Yeah.
而我們要去的地方還有其他的孩子
And where we are taking her, there are others.
難道你還看不出這意味著什麼嗎
Does that mean nothing to you?
是的 我看不出個所以然
Oh yeah, yeah it means nothing to me.
尤其是當我知道那個護士
Especially since nurse Gabriella...
說的伊甸園是根據漫畫胡編亂造出來的之後
made all that eaten shit up off the fucking comic Books.
你在說些什麼
What are you talking about?
該吃藥了 拿兩片給他
Give those, Take out two pills and give them to him.
- 羅根 羅根  - 把藥給她
- Logan, Logan.  - Give 'em to him.
快點
Now!
張嘴我看看
I wanna see it.
該死的無人卡車
Motherfucking auto trucks.
別爆粗口 羅根
Language Logan.
你衝著一台機器發火幹嘛
And you're screaming at a machine.
幹嘛 她可以殺人不眨眼卻聽不得髒話嗎
Now what? She can gut a man with a fitch can't hear a few naughty words.
我們可以教她成為更好的人
She can learn to be better.
你是說和我比嗎
You mean, better than me?
一點兒沒錯
Actually yes.
還有 勞拉腳上的爪子
And by the way, Laura's foot claws are
很顯然是由於性別所致
the obvious result of her gender.
是嗎
Is that a fact?
在獅群當中 母獅子
In a pride of lions, the females...
既要負責捕獵 又要負責照顧獅群
is both hunter and care giver.
真長知識
Good to Know.
她們用前爪捕獵
She uses her front claws for hunting...
用後爪防禦
and back claws defensively.
是嗎
Oh yeah?
這樣才能倖存下來
Thus ensuring their survival.
嘿 嘿
Hey hey!
我們得幫他們一把
We should help them.
不 我們得趕路 有人會來幫忙的
No we have to keep going. Someone will come along.
不就是我們嗎
Someone has come along.
嘿 要幫忙嗎
Hey, you need a hand?
準備好 推
Ready? Go!
很好 搞定了
Good, got it!
好了 我們回家吧
Come on, Let's get home.
勞拉
Laura!
謝謝你們的幫忙
Thanks so much for your help.
- 我叫凱瑟琳  - 詹姆斯
- I'm Kathryn.  - James.
我兒子內特
He's my son Nate.
- 嗨  - 嘿
- Hi. - Hey.
那是你女兒？
That's your daughter?
對 她叫勞拉 那是我父親
Oh yeah, that's Laura, and that's my dad...
查克
Chuck.
好了 勞拉 該走了
Come on, Laura, let's go.
我想請你們到我們家吃頓晚飯以示感謝
Well, can we show our appreciation, treat 3 of you a decent meal?
我們家離這兒不遠
We don't live far from here.
那真是太好了
That would be lovely.
我是萊斯博士
My name is Dr. Rice.
如果你喜歡也可以叫我桑德爾
But you can call me Xander if you like.
我同事告訴我你不太願意配合我們
My colleague tells me you have been some of resistant.
他說你給他的消息總是不及時
He believes you've been dispensing delayed information.
所以你的朋友總是快我們一步
To allow your friends to stay one step ahead.
我現在是在給你贖罪的機會 卡利班
I'm offering you with possibility of redemption, Caliban.
去保護這個世界 同時拯救你的朋友
To protect the world and in the process, save your friends.
而那個小女孩兒只是一個小小的代價而已
The girl is a small price to pay for that.
她不是你的同類
Unlike you, she isn't pure.
她不是天生的變種人
She was not made by nature.
她只是我犯下的一個錯誤
She's a mistake of my own.
我盡了全力 可他們用光照我 打我
I did what I could and they burned me and beat me.
你的同事都是群野蠻人
Your colleagues are savages.
我同意
I agree.
那些掠奪者都是群廢物
The Reavers were very ineffective
不過我帶了新的幫手來
But I'm bringing new tools to bear.
可我還是需要有人為我們指明方向
But I still need someone to point us in the right direction.
不 我幫不了你
No, I can't help you.
別激動 別激動
Breath, Breath.
那個老頭現在情況有多糟糕？
What does he have? the old man?
老天癡呆 漸凍癥？
Alzheimers? ALS?
世界上最危險的大腦居然得了腦退化
A degenerative brain disease in the world's most dangerous brain.
真是造化弄人
What a combo.
感謝上帝 賜予我們食物
Thank you God, for this food...
還有感謝我們的新朋友
And for our new friends, the Howletts.
感謝他們的幫忙
They came to our aid.
- 阿門  - 阿門
- Amen.  - Amen.
阿門 給你查爾斯
Amen, Here you go.
多謝
Thank you sir.
如果她想吃還有很多
Well, there is plenty more if she wants.
不用了 謝謝
She is fine. Thank you.
菜的味道很好
This is delicious.
- 謝謝  - 真的很好吃
- Thank you.  - So good.
你們要去哪裏？
Where are you all headed?
- 俄勒岡州  - 南達科他州
- Oregon.  - Ah. South Dakota.
先去俄勒岡 然後再去南達科他
Well, Oregon and then South Dakota.
去度假嗎
Vacation?
沒錯
Yes.
計劃了很久了
Long overdue.
我們住在城市裏
We are city folks.
一直都想沿著公路自駕游 看看整個國家
Always wanted to do take a road trip, see the country.
還有看看不同的風土人情
Meet the people in it.
聽起來很棒
That sounds lovely.
我一直都想說服威爾去度假 都好幾年了
I'm trying to get Will here to take a vaction for years.
如果我們到處旅遊 誰來打理這個地方
Taking trips in all over the country, Who is gonna take care of this place?
沒錯 所以才讓你賣了農場
Exactly. I say let it go.
那靠什麼養家
And live off what?
上帝會眷顧我們的
The Lord will provide.
我還在等上帝賜予我一台新的打穀機呢
I'm still waiting for the Lord to provide me with a new Thresher.
反正總有一天我會去旅行的
Honestly, I love to travel someday.
我相信會有那麼一天的
Then I bet you will.
- 我可以退學  - 行了 別說得像真的一樣
- I can drop out of school.  - Ok, let's not go in that far.
我說真的
I mean I'll do it.
- 不行  - 為什麼不行
- No.  - Why not?
- 你不是想去旅行嗎 我也想  - 行了兒子
- You wanna travel, I wanna travel.  - Son. Son.
正合你意對吧
That sounds good.
簡直就是完美
It's the perfect.
為什麼想要退學呢 內特
Why would you want to do that, Nate?
注意了 他可是個創辦過學校的人
Careful, you're speaking to a man who ran a school...
還開了好多年對吧 查爾斯
for a lot of years, right, Charles?
好吧 是的 那是一所
Well, that's. It was a...
一所為特殊孩子開設的學校
It was a kind of special needs school
這個解釋不錯
That's a good description.
他也在那兒
He was there too.
對 沒錯 我還被開除過幾次
Yeah, I got kicked out a few times.
我也希望能誇你是個好學生 可我就是說不出口
I wish I could say that you were a good pupil, but the words would choke me.
真的非常感謝你們的款待 今晚真的很棒
I mean, I can't thank you enough for this. It was great.
不過我們還得趕路
But we have a long drive ahead...
可你們總得休息吧
But you need to rest, don't you?
我們會找到旅館的
Yeah, we'll find a motel.
最近的開過去也要兩個小時 條件還不怎麼樣
The nearest one is two hours and it's not even that nice.
我們樓上有個空房間可以給你父親和女兒住
We have a perfectly fine room upstairs for your father and your daughter...
而你可以睡在客廳的折疊沙發上
and you can sleep in the living room on the convertible.
凱瑟琳 真的很感謝 不過我們還是不打擾了
Kathryn, it's very very nice of you, but we probably should go.
我們可以明天一早再走
We can leave early in the morning.
天一亮就走 你覺得呢
Break of dawn, does that work?
好吧 那我給你洗漱一下吧 老爸
Ok, why don't we wash off pop?
好的
Okay.
坐下
Sit down.
寶貝 要來點甜品嗎
Sweetie, you want some dessert?
兩天的路程 就吃了一頓飯 還幾乎沒睡過覺
Two days on the road, only one meal and hardly any sleep.
她才11歲 而我90了
She is 11 and I'm fucking 90.
可我們有101個理由繼續趕路
There is 101 reasons to keep moving.
我不是一盒牛油果 羅根
I'm not a box of avocados, Logan.
所以呢 過了今晚然後呢
stay the night, then what?
然後我們帶她去伊甸園找她的朋友
Then we take her to her friends in Eden.
然後 然後我們就去買逐日號
And then, then we bought the Sun Seeker.
先吃藥
Take the pills.
見鬼
Shit!
- 怎麼了  - 內特
- What's going on?  - Nate!
趁還有點水壓快去把浴缸放滿
Go fill the tub before we lose pressure.
親愛的 檢查下水槽
Honey, check the sink.
他們就是不肯罷休
They are just not doing this legal.
你最好現在就去處理一下
Well you might as well handle it now.
等到明天早上吧 昨晚剛下過雨
We can wait till the morning. We just had rain.
可家裏還有客人 還有一大堆碟子沒洗
We got three house guests and a sink full of dishes.
好吧 好吧
All right. All right.
供水站離這裏大概一英里半
The pumping station that supplies us is a  mile and half.
有的時候它會停止運作
Sometimes it get itself shut off.
- 是那群混蛋  - 嘿
- That asshole.  - Hey!
別亂動
Don't.
我兒子可以和你一起去
My son is happy to go with you.
不 不 不 沒關係
No, no, no, that's fine.
那些人有的時候不太...
The men that do this sometimes they can be...
- 我和你一起去  - 不 你得做作業
- I can go.  - No, you got homework.
我和你去
Okay, I'll go.
讓我先安頓好我爸爸
Just let me get my dad settled.
來吧
Night.
有電視 要看嗎
You want TV? there is TV here.
- 不用了  - 好吧
- I'm fine.  - Ok
好好休息
Get some rest.
知道嗎 羅根
You know, Logan?
生活就應該像這樣
This is what a life looks like.
一個家 家人彼此相愛
A home, people love each other.
安全的港灣
A safe place.
你應該花時間感受一下
You should take a moment and feel it.
對 這兒很好
Yeah. It's great.
羅根 羅根
Logan. Logan!
你還有時間
You still have time.
查爾斯 世界已經變了樣了
Charles, the world is not the same as it was.
待在這裏我們會有風險 你知道的
We are takin a riskin' around here, you know that.
還有我們要去的那個伊甸園
And where we're going, Eden...
其實並不存在
doesn't exist.
它是護士從漫畫書上看來的
Her nurse got it from a comic book.
你懂了嗎 都是假的
You understand? It's not real.
對勞拉來說是真的
It is for Laura.
好好休息
Get some rest.
坎伍德飲料公司買下了這裏的一切 除了我們的農場
Canewood beverage bought everything out here except for us.
我們不想賣 他們就想強行徵用
When we wouldn't sell, They tried on their domain
然後斷我們的水源
They screw with our water.
幾個月前有人下毒殺死了我們的狗
A couple of months ago, somebody poisoned our dogs.
所以今天在公路上也不是意外？
So out on the highway. those trucks?
我不知道 或許吧
Who knows. Maybe.
看看他們
Hey, look at them.
就像一隻四肢發達頭腦簡單的恐龍
They are like dinosaures with their 20 tons body and tiny little brains.
在給他們的超級轉基因玉米剝殼
shucking their crammed super corn.
那玩意兒味道簡直像屎一樣
And all tastes like shit too.
那為什麼還有人吃
Why do people eat it?
不是吃的 是用來喝的 玉米糖漿 加了那東西
They don't, they Drink it. Corn syrup. It's those thing everyone have...
他們就能保持清醒 很有精神 還能帶來性慾什麼的
to stay awake, cheer up, feel strong, sexy, whatever.
今時不同往日了 它能讓你一杯解千愁
Used to be a time, when a bad day was just a bad day.
可惜對我沒用
Mine's still on.
這些是套牛比賽贏來的
Those are for breakaway roping.
那些事繞桶比賽得來的
Those are for barrel racing...
還有這些 繞桿比賽得來的
and right here this for poll painting
不過全是二三等獎
They are all second and third place.
我不是很在行 不過我爸爸硬要我參加
I'm not so good, but my dad makes me.
你想聽嗎
Do you want to listen?
喜歡嗎
You like it?
給 借你聽一晚
Here, you can take it for tonight...
明早你再還給我
and I'll get it back from you in the morning.
看來得弄一會兒了
Looks like we're gonna be here a while.
能撐一陣子
That'll hold it?
沒錯
Yeah.
撐到下一次
Until next time.
謝謝
Thanks.
那麼 你女兒那樣有多久了
So, how long your daughter's been like that?
- 什麼  - 不說話
- What?  - Mute.
從一開始就這樣
Since the beginning.
其實我還挺羨慕你的
Hey, in a lot of ways, I envy you.
等她到了內特的年紀就不會說些蠢話了
they get to be Nate's age, the nonsence that comes out of their mouths
讓你懷疑做父母的意義何在
makes you wonder the whole point of all.
見鬼
Shit.
別擔心 不會用上槍的
Don't worry. We won't need it.
待在這兒
Stay here.
晚上好 芒森先生
Good evening, Mr. Munson.
什麼風把你吹來了
What brings you out this way?
你為什麼不問問你的手下
Why don't you ask your boys.
芒森先生 你知道你這樣是非法入侵吧
Mr. Munson, you understand you're tresspassing right now, right?
我和這裏以前的主人簽訂過地役權
I have a easement with the previous owner of the property.
胡扯
Bullshit.
你也說是「前」主人了
Previous being the operative word
他是誰？
Who is this?
勸你趕緊回車上去的好心人
Just a guy telling you to get back in your nice truck.
到別的地方去扮你的地痞流氓
Go play # at somewhere else.
嘿 卡爾
Hey, Carl...
看來芒森先生雇了一個打手
Looks like Mr Munson hired some muscle.
看起來是的
Looks that way.
他只是我的朋友
He is a friend of mine.
你朋友口氣挺大
A friend with big mouth.
這話我聽得多了
I hear that a lot.
那你肯定也聽過這個吧
Then you probably hear this too.
多了去了
More than I like.
那你知道該怎麼做了
Then you know the drill!
我數三下
On my count to three...
你們給我離開這兒
and you're gonna start walking away.
這裏的水我有權使用
I got a right to this water.
- 一  - 我請了律師
- One.  - I have a lawyer now.
二
Two.
三
Three.
頭兒 你還好嗎
You all right, boss?
知道該怎麼做了吧
You know the drill.
趕緊給我滾
Get the hell outta here.
- 頭兒？  - 去你的
- Okay, boss?  - Fuck off.
滾
Go.
你受過訓練
You got a training.
算是吧
Some.
先別叫醒她
Hey, don't wake her yet.
讓她再睡一小時
Let her sleep another hour
知道嗎 羅根
You know, Logan?
毫無疑問 今天晚上
This was without a doubt...
是我這麼久以來度過的最美好的夜晚
the most perfect night I've had in a very long time.
可我並不配擁有它 不是嗎
But I don't deserve it. do I.
我做過一些事
I did something.
一些不可言說的事
Something unspeakable.
發生在維斯切斯特的事我全記起來了
I have remembered what happened in Westchester.
這已經不是我第一次傷害別人了
This is not the first time I've hurt people.
只是在今天之前 我一直都不知道
Until today, I did not know.
你也不告訴我
You wouldn't tell me.
所以我們就這樣一直逃避下去
So we just, kept from... running away from.
我想我終於能理解你了
I think I finally understand you.
羅根
Logan...
他簡直完美
It's fantastic.
你說過你只要那個女孩兒
You said you only needed the girl!
我也說過我帶了新幫手來
I told you I swear to bring new tool to ...
我給過你朋友機會 你也是
Your friends had every chance, so did you.
內特
Nate?
放下她
Put her down
親愛的
Honey.
別上來 威爾
Stay down there, Will!
住手
Stop.
凱瑟琳
Kathryn!
查爾斯
Charles!
按住傷口
Hold this.
那不是我 那不是我
It wasn't me. It wasn't me.
他來了
Here he comes.
我可以過去接他
I could pick em up. meet him halfway.
不 讓他們過來
No no no. Let him come to us.
X-23很不好對付
We struggled with the X-23s.
我們本以為能把這些孩子
We assumed because they were children...
從小培養成冷血殺手
We could raise them without a conscience.
可憤怒是無法後天培養的
But you can't manage her rage.
你必須從一開始就為他設定好
You simply design it from scratch.
那又是該死的誰
Who the fuck is that?
威爾·芒森
Will Munson!
堅持住 查爾斯
Hold on, Charles.
芒森 該死的 給我出來
Munson, goddammit, come out here!
芒森
Munson!
快給我出來
Come out here now!
給我滾出來 芒森
Come out here now, Munson.
是剛才那個混蛋
There's that asshole.
你好 混蛋
Oi, asshole.
聽著 過去的事我就不計較了
Listen, I'm willing to let bygones be bygones.
我不知道芒森那傢伙付你多少錢
I do not know what Munson's paying you..
我們坎伍德現在給你5000美元
but Canewood can start you out at Five G.
我指一星期
A week that is.
你最好待著別動 兄弟
You better stay where you are pal.
我就是這裏的法律
I'm the law out here.
不 不 不
No no no.
天殺的
What the hell!
我靠
Oh Shit!
快開槍
Shoot him!
我們得介入了
We need to intervene.
可他只聽你的話 博士
Well he only listens to you, Doc.
24!
快回來
Get back here!
住手 趕緊住手
Stop! stop Now!
快按住傷口 按緊
Hold it still right now tight.
- 我們的船  - 什麼
- Our boat.  - What?
逐日號
The sun seeker.
不
No.
回來
Come!
24!
快來人幫我
need some help out here.
看來我們得出手了
I guess we have to take care this now.
把那個給我
Give me that.
聽到沒 你到底在幹什麼
What the fuck do you think you're doing?
給我
Come!
回來
Now!
把她帶上
Pick her up.
小心光
Beware of the light.
你到底是什麼
What the hell are you?
坐下
Sit down.
別亂動
Hold still.
沒事了 沒事了
It's all right, it's all right.
你做得很好 24
You did fine 24.
你正在癒合 保持呼吸
You are healing. Just breathe.
嚴格來說 你還只是個新生兒
You're a new born, by any measure.
保持呼吸
Just breathe.
你的身體還有許多工作要完成
Your body has work to do.
它需要止血 生成血管 還有表皮
Haemostasis, angiogenesis, epithelialization...
增生基質細胞
Stroma cell proliferization.
這能幫助你恢復
This will help you heal.
讓你變得更強
Make you stronger.
好吧
Well...
這裏也算得上是傍水了
It got water and...
至少有水
It's got water.
該死 該死
Fuck. Fuck.
Fuck! Fuck!
該死
Fuck!
見鬼
Shit!
去死 去死
Fuck! Fuck!
去死
Fuck!
去你的
Motherfucking...!
見鬼
Shit!
去死
Fuck! Fuck!
歡迎回來
Welcome back.
我剛才還在想 是不是該告訴
I was starting to think I was gonna have to tell
休息室那小女孩兒
that nice little girl out in the waiting room...
她爸爸醒不過來了
her daddy's gone.
我一直希望
I had always hoped...
能有機會遇到像你這樣的人
that I get the chance to meet someone like you.
你的同類已經不多了
Just a few you left.
我也很高興認識你 醫生
Nice to meet you too, doctor.
可我必須得趕路了
But I really gotta get on my way.
不 不 不 別這樣
No, do not do that.
你需要休息 還有治療
What you need is rest and treatment.
你需要找個地方檢查一下
You need to check yourself in somewhere.
- 我沒事  - 不 你有事
- I'll be fine.  - No, you're not!
我是說 我知道你與眾不同
I know that you're different...
不過這也無法改變你體內有東西在荼毒你的事實
but that doesn't change the fact that something inside you is poisoned.
你得趙家醫院檢查一下
You got to check youself into a hospital.
看看到底怎麼回事
Find out what it is.
我知道怎麼回事
I know what it is.
求你了先生 如果你不想去醫院的話 或許我可以幫你
Please Mr, if you don't want to go to a hospital, maybe I can help you.
我可以幫你做測試
Maybe I can run some tests.
聽著 醫生 你看起來是個好人
Look, Doc. You seem like a nice guy.
如果你想要救人的話 救你自己吧
You want to save a life? save your own.
忘了我們來過這兒
Forget we were here.
我們走
Let's go.
你不能隨便拿別人的
You can't just take..
我不知道你怎麼帶我來這兒的 不過
I don't know how you got me here but..
謝謝
Thank you.
好的
Yeah.
你會說話
You can talk?
見鬼
What the fuck..?
那為什麼
Why the fuck...?
我們開了2000英里你一個字都不說
What's all this bullshit Being for last 2000 fucking miles?
什麼 好吧
What? Shut up.
行了 閉嘴 給我閉嘴
Shut up, Shut the fuck up!
什麼 他們是誰
What? Who is that?
他們是誰
Who is that?
北達科他州
North Dakota.
什麼
What?
這個地方 對吧
This place. Ok?
你的護士 漫畫書看多了 明白嗎
Your nurse, she read too many stories, you understand?
漫畫書看太多了
Too many stories!
我看了 我看過了 懂嗎
I've seen it! I've seen it, okay?
這上面畫的
This all here...
所有的一切都不存在 明白了嗎
None of this..no no existo! Okay, you understand me?
上面的伊甸園 根本不存在
This Eden does not exist. No no.
那是虛構的 孩子看到沒
It's a fantasy. You can't see that?
上面寫著畫這些漫畫的人的名字
Those are the names of people who just made this...
這些都是他們編出來的
They made this whole thing up.
懂嗎 這整個
Okay? this whole..
整個故事 一小部分是真的 其他的都是他們編出來的
It happened once, and they just turned it into a big fucking lie.
僅此而已 不
All this is. No!
見鬼
Fuck.
不
No.
我知道 我理解
I know, I understand.
這條路非常遠
This is a long away.
明白嗎 我不會送你去北達科他州
You understand? I am not taking you to North Dakota.
我撐不下去了 我沒法送你去那兒
I am fucked up. And I can not get you there.
還要兩天的路程 我不會送你去的
It is a two day drive And I am not taking...
夠了 別打了
Don't fucking hit me!
別再打了
Don't hit me!
別再念這些名字
Stop saying those names.
聽到沒 別再念了
And stop saying those names.
停下
Stop!
好吧 好吧
Fine fine!
你想要去是吧 我就帶你去
You wanna go in there? I'll take you there.
你自己親眼去看
..See for yourself.
一起去你那該死的童話世界
Let's got a Fucking fantasy land.
我們知道控制局勢的重要性 萊斯博士
We understand the importance of containment, Dr. Rice.
可是不能像你之前在華瑞茲那樣大動干戈啊
But You can not leave a war zone behind like you did in Juarez.
你可別忘了 這些都是殺人機器
Try to remind yourself these all are killing machines.
輕易就能殺掉你全家
Machines would happily disembowed your family
不都是啊
Not all.
我跟你說了把他們解決掉 不管死活
I just told you put these assets off board, dead or live.
你改了我的命令嗎
You changing my brief?
沒有
No.
那還廢什麼話
Why then?
提取他的細胞組織
Dissect tissues from this one.
他擅長追蹤 具有高智商
He's good tracker, and had a high IQ.
拿去吧
Here you go.
讓我開
Let me drive.
那可不行
Absolutely not.
別盯著我看
Quit looking at me.
你快死了
You're dying.
你想死
You want to die.
查爾斯告訴我的
Charles told me.
他還告訴了你什麼
What else did he tell you?
別讓你死
Do not let you.
休息吧
Rest.
穩住
Keep it steady.
往我這邊來點
Swing him toward me.
慢點
Easy.
這樣可以嗎 瑞克多
Is this good, Rictor
不用那麼多 少點兒
Not so much, less.
我在哪兒
Where am I?
這是什麼
What is it?
從哪兒弄來的
Where did you get that?
從我們來的地方
Where we came from.
戰鬥時他們給我們這個 讓我們變得更強
They gave it to us when we were fighting. It makes you stronger.
那東西只會讓你發狂
It makes you crazy is what it does.
還會殺了你
It'll kill you.
不 如果你控制好劑量的話
No, Not if you use it in small doses.
它會幫你恢復
It's helping you heal.
勞拉在哪兒
Where is Laura?
她在下面睡著了
She is sleeping down there.
要我叫醒她嗎
Do You want me to wake her up?
不
No.
你做噩夢了
You had a nightmare.
你會做噩夢嗎
Do you have nightmares?
夢裏有人會傷害我
People hurt me.
我的不一樣
Mine are different.
夢裏我傷害了別人
I hurt people.
這個是什麼
你知道這是什麼嗎
You know what it is?
這是用艾德曼合金做的
It's made of adamantium.
就是他們注入我們體內的東西
It's what they put inside of us.
所以它能殺死我們
So it can kill us.
或許正是它在要我的命
Probably what's killing me now.
這是我很久以前得到的
I got this a long time ago...
我留著它是想提醒我 自己究竟是誰
I kept it as a reminder of what I am.
現在我留著...
Now I keep it to...
實話說
actually I...
我想過用它來自殺
I was thinking of shooting myself.
查爾斯說得沒錯
Like Charles said.
我也傷害過人
I have hurt people too.
你得學會如何面對這種感覺
You gonna have to learn how to live with that.
他們都是壞人
They were bad people.
並沒有差別
All the same.
不好玩 這一點都不好玩
It's not funny. That's not funny!
嘿 小子
Hey! Hey pal.
我睡了多久了
How long have I been out?
我在床上躺了多久了
How long have I been in that bed?
兩天
Two days.
進去告訴大家可以開始打包了
Go inside and tell everyone to get packing.
你們不能這樣 不能坐以待斃
You can't do this, you can not just stay here.
我們必須等待 計劃就是這樣的
We had to wait. It was the plan.
今天是我們集合的最後一天
And everyone had till today to find their way here.
再等下去 阿爾卡利會找到你們 然後把你們全部殺掉
If you keep waiting, Alkali will find you and they kill you all.
你們得離開這兒
You need to get out!
明天天亮前我們就走
We are leaving tomorrow before dawn.
我們會穿過邊界去加拿大
We gonna cross the border.
那裏有避難所
It's a safe heaven
請確認坐標
Seeing coordinates?
已確認 正午到五點之間
Yes, between noon and 5..
- 你們的庇護要求已批准  - 收到
- Your asylum are approved.  - Copy.
你往右邊看 勞拉
Swing it to your right, Laura.
再往右一點 對
A little more. Yes.
看到樹林了嗎
You see the Woods?
要走8英里才能到那兒
It's a 8 miles hike though here.
看到那條通道沒
You see that pass?
那就是邊屆
That's the border.
到那裏我們就安全了
That's where we'll be safe.
進來吧
Come inside.
勞拉告訴我你為她所做的一切
Laura told me all that you did for her.
她很幸運有你在她身邊
She was lucky to have you.
拿著吧 她說這是你的
Take it. She says it's yours.
這也是你送她來的目的吧
It's why you did it, right?
對 好吧
Yeah, well...
可我不需要了 你們留著吧
Look, I do not need it. You do. okay?
隨你便吧
Suit yourself.
能給我一個嗎
Can I have one?
- 給  - 謝謝
- Here.  - Thanks
你的朋友們看起來不錯
Your friends they seem nice.
讓我想起了當年
Kind of reminds me of...
發生什麼事了
Hey, hey, what's going on?
你已經找到同伴了
You're with your pals. You made it.
你要去哪裏
Where will you go?
先去最近的酒吧看看
Nearest bar for start.
我已經把你送到了 我的使命完成了
Hey, I got you here. That was all I signed up for.
我還把錢還給你了
Even gave back the money.
你還真是個好人
Such a nice man.
這並不是我想要的
Hey, I never asked for this.
懂嗎 這也不是查爾斯想要的
All right? Charles did not ask for this.
這也不是卡利班想要的
Caliban never asked for this.
現在他們都躺在了土裏
And they are six feet under the ground.
我不知道查爾斯給你灌輸了什麼
I do not know what Charles put into your head...
反正我不是你心裏想的那樣 懂嗎
but I'm not whatever it is you think I am. OK?
我認識你不過一個星期
I don't even met you like a week ago.
你找到了你的麗貝卡 你的黛利拉
You got your Rebecca, your Delilah...
還有其他亂七八糟的人
your blah, blah, or whatever
你想要的都已經得到了
Everything you've asked for you've got it.
而且這樣更好
And it is better this way.
因為我總是搞砸
Because I suck at this.
厄運總會降臨在我在乎的人身上
Bad shit happens to people I care about.
你懂嗎
You understand me?
我不會有事的
Then I'll be fine.
快跑 羅比 快跑
Run, Bobby, run!
快 快
Go! Go!
再快點
Go faster.
在他們越過邊界前 我們得抓住他們
We should reach them before they get to the border.
行動
Move out!
我們走 我們走
Let's go! Let's go!
跑 快跑
Run! Run!
快跑
Run!
盡量呼吸
I want you to breath.
只是皮肉傷 小子
Just a flesh wound baby
她在這兒
There she is!
抓住她了
We got her!
躲在我身後
Get behind me!
你把藥全用上了
You took all the medicine.
藥效就快退了
It's wearing off.
到你朋友那兒去
Go to your friends.
去吧
Go.
勞拉
Laura?
我會告訴你時機
You'll know when.
九點方向
9'o clock!
綠色液體的藥效快沒了吧
The green juice is wearing off huh?
看來對於老變種人來說藥效還真短
You know, for a old mutant it's got a short high.
很快你會連爪子都神不出來
Hard to keep your claws out sometime.
滅了這混蛋 羅根
Waste this dick, Logan!
請住手 豪利特先生
Please stop, Mr. Howlett.
不然我就得下令朝孩子們開火了
I'm gonna have to tell this men to fire on these children.
你也不想這樣吧
You don't want that.
你也知道血清的藥效很快就沒了
I can see the effect of the serum wearing off.
再受傷的話你就活不成了
You will not survive for the wounds
請允許我自我介紹一下
Allow me to introduce myself.
我叫桑德爾·萊斯
Zander Rice.
我想你應在X武器項目中見過我父親
I believe you knew my father on the weapon x program.
沒錯 就是那個混蛋把毒藥注入我體內的
Yeah. he's the asshole who put this poison in me.
對 混蛋之一
Yes, he was one of them.
那他應該已經被我殺了
I think I might have killed him.
你說得沒錯
I think you're right.
放尊重些 變種人
Why don't you show some respect, muty.
你眼前的這位可是消滅了所有變種人的人
Your'e looking at the man who wiped up your kind.
我的朋友唐納德言過其實了
My friend Donald overstates.
他把事情說得過分殘忍了
He makes it sound more brutal than intended.
我的目的不是消滅變種人
But that was not to end mutant kind...
而是掌控他們
but to control it.
我意識到我們不該放棄在飲食上的研發
I've realized we needn't stop perfecting what we eat and drink.
我們可以用這些產品來完善自己
We could use that as part to perfect ourselves.
從飲料到穀物早餐 在每樣東西中
To distribute Gene therapy discreetly through everything..
謹慎地進行基因治療
from sweet drinks to breakfast cereals.
而且成功了
And it worked.
隨機出現的變種基因 就像小兒麻痹一樣被扼殺了
Random mutantcy went the way of polio.
然後我們開始了下一步
We embarked on our next endeavour
培育你們自己的變種人
Grow mutants of your own.
正是
precisely.
世道艱難 你不能
These are dangerous times, James. You can't.
該你上場了 小子
Show time, boy!
起來 小子 起來 小子
Get up, boy, get up, boy!
是他殺的 快起來
He did that. Get up!
勞拉 不
Laura! No!
勞拉
Laura!
快走
Go!
快 快 快
Go! Go! Go!
快走 離開這兒 快
Go! Get out of here! Go!
快走 快 快 快
Go! Go! Go! Go!
快走
Go go!
快跑
Run!
不
No!
帶上你的朋友 快跑
Take your friends and run
不
No.
他們還會派人來追殺你們
They'll keep coming.
聽著 你們不必再戰鬥了
Listen, you don't have to fight anymore.
走
Go!
別成為他們所希望的那樣
Don't be what they made you.
勞拉 勞拉
Laura... Laura...
爸爸
daddy.
原來 死亡是這種感覺
Ah, so this is what it feels like.
不
No!
爸爸
daddy!
人必須忠於自己 喬伊
A man has to be what he is, Joey.
不能違背自己的本性
Can't break the moulds.
帶著殺戮活下去很難
There is no living with a killing...
這條路沒有退路
There is no going back.
是對是錯 你都得背負
Right or wrong, it's a brand.
直至一生
A brand sticks.
現在快回去找你媽媽
Now you run on home to your mother
告訴她一切都好
and tell her everything's all right
山谷裏再也不會有槍聲了
There are no more guns in the Valley
走吧 繼續上路
Let's go. We gotta move.
金剛狼3：殊死一戰
字幕製作：anti